<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd">
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<rfc category="std" docName="draft-looker-jwm-01"
     ipr="trust200902">

  <front>
    <title abbrev="jwm">JSON Web Message</title>

    <author fullname="Tobias Looker" 
            initials="T." role="editor"
            surname="Looker">
      <organization>Mattr</organization>
      <address>
        <email>tobias.looker@mattr.global</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date day="21" month="December" year="2019"/>

    <abstract>
      <t>JSON Web Message (JWM) is a flexible way to encode application-level messages in JSON
      for transfer over a variety of transport protocols. JWMs use JSON Web
      Encryption (JWE) to protect integrity, achieve confidentiality, and achieve repudiable authentication;
      alternatively or in addition, they use JSON Web Signatures (JWS) to associate messages with a non-repudiable
      digital signature.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">
      <t>JSON Web Message (JWM) is a flexible way to encode application-level messages in JSON
        for transfer over a variety of transport protocols. JWMs use JSON Web
        Encryption (JWE) to protect integrity, achieve confidentiality, and achieve repudiable authentication;
        alternatively or in addition, they use JSON Web Signatures (JWS) to associate messages with a non-repudiable
        digital signature. JWMs are inspired by JWTs <xref target="RFC7519"/>; more details about this relationship
        are documented in <xref target="relationship-to-jwt"/>.</t>

      <section anchor="notational-conventions" title="Notational Conventions">
        <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
        "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and
        "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as described in BCP 14
        <xref target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref> <xref target="RFC8174">RFC
        8174</xref> when, and only when, they appear in all capitals, as shown
        here.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="terminology" title="Terminology">
        <t>The terms "JSON Web Signature (JWS)", "Base64url Encoding", "Header Parameter", "JOSE Header", 
        "JWS Payload", "JWS Signature", "JWS Compact Serialization" and "JWS JSON Serialization" are defined 
        by the JWS specification <xref target="RFC7515"/>.</t>

        <t>The terms "JSON Web Encryption (JWE)", "JWE Compact Serialization" and "JWE JSON Serialization" 
        are defined by the JWE specification <xref target="RFC7516"/>.</t>

        <t>The terms "StringOrURI", "NumericDate" are defined by the JWT specification <xref target="RFC7519"/>.</t>

        <t>The following terms are defined by this specification:</t>

        <t>
          <list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="JSON Web Message">A JWM Attribute Set, encoded in a JWS and/or JWE, enabling it to be digitally signed and/or encrypted.</t>

            <t hangText="JWM Attribute Set">A JSON object of attributes conveyed by the JWM.</t>

            <t hangText="Attribute">A piece of information conveyed in a message, sent from a sender intended for processing by one or more
            recipients. An attribute is represented in a JWM Attribute Set as a name/value pair consisting of an Attribute Name and an Attribute Value.</t>

            <t hangText="Attribute Name">The name portion of an attribute representation. An attribute name is always a string.</t>

            <t hangText="Attribute Value">The value portion of an attribute representation. An attribute value can be any JSON value.</t>

            <t hangText="Nested JWM">A JWM in which nested signing and/or encryption is employed. In Nested JWMs, a JWM is used as the payload 
            or plaintext value of an enclosing JWS or JWE structure, respectively.</t>
          </list>
        </t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="json-web-message-jwm-overview" title="JSON Web Message (JWM) Overview">
      <section anchor="relationship-to-jwt" title="Relationship to JWT">

        <t>JWMs conceptually share parallels to JWTs:</t>
          <t>
            <list style="symbols">
              <t>A JWM contains a JSON object comprised of attributes known as a JWM Attribute Set, where the attributes featured in the set can be public, private
              or registered in an IANA registry. This is conceptually parallel to claims in JWTs, the JWT Claim Set, and the JWT claims IANA registry.</t>
              
              <t>A JWM leverages JSON Web Signature (JWS) and or JSON Web Encryption (JWE) to achieve digital signing, integrity protection and 
              or confidentiality via encryption for the JWM attribute set in similar ways to JWT for the JWT claim set.</t>
            </list>
          </t>

          <t>JWMs also deviate from JWTs in important ways that prevent a converged specification.</t>
            <t>
              <list style="symbols">
                <t>JWM and JWT have different intents. A JWM is about a sender creating a message composed of attributes, where the message is destined for a
                  recipient or recipients. Whereas a JWT is about an issuer expressing claims about a subject to an audience.</t>

                <t>The primary usage of JWTs centers around creating tokens that are digitally signed or integrity protected through a Message Authentication Code
                  (MAC) by leveraging JWS. Encrypted JWTs via JWE are less common and as defined in Section 8 of <xref target="RFC7519"/>
                  they are optional to implement. Whereas JWMs require both JWS and JWE implementations.</t>

                <t>Because JWTs must be compact and URL-safe, they require compact serialization for both
                JWS and JWE representations. This means JWTs can feature only a single
                digital signature, and/or encrypt for only a single recipient. In contrast, JWMs support multiple
                digital signatures, and encryption for multiple recipients. They achieve this
                using the JSON-based serialization of JWS and JWE.</t>

                <t>JWTs support an insecure format as defined in Section 6 of <xref target="RFC7519"/>, JWMs do not allow this format
                due to the vulnerabilities it introduces.</t>
              </list>
            </t>

          <t>In the spirit of specification re-use and promoting ease of understanding, this specification's structure is inspired by <xref target="RFC7519"/>.</t>
      </section>
      
      <section anchor="example-signed-jwm" title="Example Signed JWM">
        <t>The following example JOSE Header declares that the object is a JWM, and the JWM is a JWS that has been digitally signed using 
        ECDSA with the curve p-256 and SHA-256 as the hashing algorithm ("ES256"). The signer of the JWM has indicated that the key used
        to sign the JWM is identified by "Ef1sFuyOozYm3CEY4iCdwqxiSyXZ5Br-eUDdQXk6jaQ" (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{"typ":"JWM",
 "kid":"Ef1sFuyOozYm3CEY4iCdwqxiSyXZ5Br-eUDdQXk6jaQ",
 "alg":"ES256"}]]></artwork></figure>

        <t>Base64url encoding the octets of the UTF-8 representation of the JOSE
        Header yields this encoded JOSE Header value (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <t>eyJ0eXAiOiJKV00iLCJraWQiOiJFZjFzRnV5T296WW0zQ0VZNGlDZHdxeGlTeVhaNUJyLWVVRGRRWGs2amFRIiwiYWxnIjoiRVMyNTYifQ</t>

        <t>The following is an example of a JWM Attributes Set (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{"id":"urn:uuid:ef5a7369-f0b9-4143-a49d-2b9c7ee51117",
 "type":"hello-world-message-type",
 "from":"urn:uuid:8abdf5fb-621e-4cf5-a595-071bc2c91d82", 
 "expires_time":1516239022,
 "created_time":1516269022,
 "body":{"message": "Hello world!"}}]]></artwork></figure>

        <t>Base64url encoding the octets of the UTF-8 the JWS Payload yields this encoded JWS Payload (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <t>eyJpZCI6InVybjp1dWlkOmVmNWE3MzY5LWYwYjktNDE0My1hNDlkLTJiOWM3ZWU1MTExNyIsInR5cGUiOiJoZWxsby13b3JsZC1tZXNzYWdlLXR5cGUiLCJmcm9tIjoidXJuOnV1aWQ6OGFiZGY1ZmItNjIxZS00Y2Y1LWE1OTUtMDcxYmMyYzkxZDgyIiwiZXhwaXJ5IjoxNTE2MjM5MDIyLCJ0aW1lX3N0YW1wIjoxNTE2MjY5MDIyLCJib2R5Ijp7Im1lc3NhZ2UiOiJIZWxsbyB3b3JsZCEifX0</t>

        <t>Computing the signature of the encoded JOSE Header and encoded JWS Payload with the ECDSA with the curve p-256 and SHA-256 as the hashing 
        algorithm  and base64url encoding the value in the manner specified in <xref target="RFC7515"/> yields this encoded JWS Signature:</t>

        <t>UDE7NsEJyhiewrX2_Z9OdIdB2ZREauoPoUAKdEmW72d8H_ivkjC1p7G16WHunBMq1zFkanINTil3-H1FlhbzsQ</t>

        <t>Compact Serialization (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <t>eyJ0eXAiOiJKV00iLCJraWQiOiJFZjFzRnV5T296WW0zQ0VZNGlDZHdxeGlTeVhaNUJyLWVVRGRRWGs2amFRIiwiYWxnIjoiRVMyNTYifQ<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        eyJpZCI6InVybjp1dWlkOmVmNWE3MzY5LWYwYjktNDE0My1hNDlkLTJiOWM3ZWU1MTExNyIsInR5cGUiOiJoZWxsby13b3JsZC1tZXNzYWdlLXR5cGUiLCJmcm9tIjoidXJuOnV1aWQ6OGFiZGY1ZmItNjIxZS00Y2Y1LWE1OTUtMDcxYmMyYzkxZDgyIiwiZXhwaXJ5IjoxNTE2MjM5MDIyLCJ0aW1lX3N0YW1wIjoxNTE2MjY5MDIyLCJib2R5Ijp7Im1lc3NhZ2UiOiJIZWxsbyB3b3JsZCEifX0<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        UDE7NsEJyhiewrX2_Z9OdIdB2ZREauoPoUAKdEmW72d8H_ivkjC1p7G16WHunBMq1zFkanINTil3-H1FlhbzsQ</t>

        <t>JSON Serialization: (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

<figure><artwork><![CDATA[    {
      "payload": "eyJpZCI6InVybjp1dWlkOmVmNWE3MzY5LWYwYjktNDE0My1hNDl
      kLTJiOWM3ZWU1MTExNyIsInR5cGUiOiJoZWxsby13b3JsZC1tZXNzYWdlLXR5cG
      UiLCJmcm9tIjoidXJuOnV1aWQ6OGFiZGY1ZmItNjIxZS00Y2Y1LWE1OTUtMDcxY
      mMyYzkxZDgyIiwiZXhwaXJ5IjoxNTE2MjM5MDIyLCJ0aW1lX3N0YW1wIjoxNTE2
      MjY5MDIyLCJib2R5Ijp7Im1lc3NhZ2UiOiJIZWxsbyB3b3JsZCEifX0",
      "signatures": [
        {
          "protected": "eyJ0eXAiOiJKV00iLCJraWQiOiJFZjFzRnV5T296WW0zQ
          0VZNGlDZHdxeGlTeVhaNUJyLWVVRGRRWGs2amFRIiwiYWxnIjoiRVMyNTYi
          fQ",
          "signature": "rwhHoGJZRyLliF2jPqGXMddBLWlJls4XqSO21GH2itlwh
          3d3Zb2jAtqA93s9Lb6ktXoxqHxNy4Lbirtr3pCHQA"
        }
      ]
    }]]></artwork></figure>

      </section>

      <section anchor="example-encrypted-jwm" title="Example Encrypted JWM">
        <t>The following example JOSE Header declares that the object is a JWM, and the JWM is a JWE that has been encrypted using
        AES in Galois/Counter Mode (GCM) with 256-bit for content encryption (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{
 "typ":"JWM",
 "enc":"A256GCM"
}]]></artwork></figure>

        <t>The following JOSE Header declares that the sender has used Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral 
        Static (ECDH-ES+A256KW) for key agreement with AES based key wrapping to encrypt the content encryption key (CEK). The keys required
        to perform the opposite Diffie-Helman are identified by the key id of "PGoXzs0NWaR_meKgTZLbEuDoSVTaFuyrbWI7V9dpjCg"
        along with the ephemeral public key declared by the JSON object "epk". The encrypted CEK is represented by the "encrypted_key" field 
        (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{
"kid": "PGoXzs0NWaR_meKgTZLbEuDoSVTaFuyrbWI7V9dpjCg",
"alg": "ECDH-ES+A256KW",
"epk": {
  "kty": "EC",
  "crv": "P-256",
  "x": "-Nh7ShRB_xaCBZRdIiVCul3SoR0Yw4TGEQqqGij1vJs",
  "y": "9tLx81PMfQkrOw8yuI2YwI0o7MtNzaCGfCBbZBW5YrM"
}
}]]></artwork></figure>

        <t>Because the JWE features a single recipient, the two JOSE headers are combined into a single JOSE header, that can be represented as the following.</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{
  "typ": "JWM",
  "enc": "A256GCM",
  "kid": "PGoXzs0NWaR_meKgTZLbEuDoSVTaFuyrbWI7V9dpjCg",
  "alg": "ECDH-ES+A256KW",
  "epk": {
    "kty": "EC",
    "crv": "P-256",
    "x": "-Nh7ShRB_xaCBZRdIiVCul3SoR0Yw4TGEQqqGij1vJs",
    "y": "9tLx81PMfQkrOw8yuI2YwI0o7MtNzaCGfCBbZBW5YrM"
  }
}]]></artwork></figure>

        <t>The following is an example of a JWM Attributes Set (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[{"id":"urn:uuid:ef5a7369-f0b9-4143-a49d-2b9c7ee51117",
 "type":"hello-world-message-type",
 "from":"urn:uuid:8abdf5fb-621e-4cf5-a595-071bc2c91d82", 
 "expires_time":1516239022,
 "created_time":1516269022,
 "body":{"message": "Hello world!"}}]]></artwork></figure>
        
        <t>Encrypting the above plaintext for the recipient yields the following ciphertext in base64url form.</t>

        <t>awEW6ssGMbQxmvv4FPf0smom4QvPNrgLaxFiMMRXmUTgcs6mLcSJDbUhwLfGfnEeu2a0bcGLRt7tTuQij5RBIe6sflhIgOjpr3VAHdZBYJbF
        Jg9dCMW_hVk0iLytmFV5BhvqXUXDAckwwTU41PcS2_qO5uqdIe24teP8Bd_IbVeVnaUwrEEBGJvxYDTefdZ4gryrzKFsLLBD5Fr9TsCFEddg0RL
        xaXFGX1YT8Jm6Ahm-jd6Ol9qIpWx-8PMaFcZl7h4sPiAGVPiaaCyzTsMy8KW0Nmz3cEFqjEm4Ipc</t>

        <t>Composing this information into a valid JWE leads to the following possible expressions</t>

        <t>Compact Serialization (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <t>eyJ0eXAiOiJKV00iLCJlbmMiOiJBMjU2R0NNIiwia2lkIjoiUEdvWHpzME5XYVJfbWVLZ1RaTGJFdURvU1ZUYUZ1eXJiV0k3VjlkcGpDZyIsImFsZyI6I
        kVDREgtRVMrQTI1NktXIiwiZXBrIjp7Imt0eSI6IkVDIiwiY3J2IjoiUC0yNTYiLCJ4IjoiZGdMdy1wOG5kZ0xRSmhZeWhUaGhpVDRhbmJlRjhaak1MYXRxR
        2dXVGxHSSIsInkiOiJ3MkNfcjUzekdUdVZscDhQVndFZjViWWI0TWo4bXVjNTVtMHh6VkVMN1o0In19<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        rAiydPRY_cciOmaQ-tnNiacHWn2Z2GqDgf0FcG4nK2L_KsPd1V1OSA<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        EIY6u2ahL0MI28ah<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        awEW6ssGMbQxmvv4FPf0smom4QvPNrgLaxFiMMRXmUTgcs6mLcSJDbUhwLfGfnEeu2a0bcGLRt7tTuQij5RBIe6sflhIgOjpr3VAHdZBYJbF
        Jg9dCMW_hVk0iLytmFV5BhvqXUXDAckwwTU41PcS2_qO5uqdIe24teP8Bd_IbVeVnaUwrEEBGJvxYDTefdZ4gryrzKFsLLBD5Fr9TsCFEddg0RL
        xaXFGX1YT8Jm6Ahm-jd6Ol9qIpWx-8PMaFcZl7h4sPiAGVPiaaCyzTsMy8KW0Nmz3cEFqjEm4Ipc<vspace/>
        .<vspace/>
        fp_tT_6qsQK2d9szRAwWgA</t>

        <t>JSON Serialization (with line breaks for display purposes only):</t>

        <figure><artwork><![CDATA[  {
  "protected": "eyJ0eXAiOiJKV00iLCJlbmMiOiJBMjU2R0NNIiwi
  a2lkIjoiUEdvWHpzME5XYVJfbWVLZ1RaTGJFdURvU1ZUYUZ1eXJiV0
  k3VjlkcGpDZyIsImFsZyI6IkVDREgtRVMrQTI1NktXIiwiZXBrIjp7
  Imt0eSI6IkVDIiwiY3J2IjoiUC0yNTYiLCJ4IjoiLU5oN1NoUkJfeG
  FDQlpSZElpVkN1bDNTb1IwWXc0VEdFUXFxR2lqMXZKcyIsInkiOiI5
  dEx4ODFQTWZRa3JPdzh5dUkyWXdJMG83TXROemFDR2ZDQmJaQlc1WX
  JNIn19",
  "recipients": [
    {
      "encrypted_key": "J1Fs9JaDjOT_5481ORQWfEZmHy7OjE3p
      TNKccnK7hlqjxbPalQWWLg"
    }
  ],
  "iv": "u5kIzo0m_d2PjI4m",
  "ciphertext": "qGuFFoHy7HBmkf2BaY6eREwzEjn6O_FnRoXj2H-
  DAXo1PgQdfON-_1QbxtnT8e8z_M6Gown7s8fLtYNmIHAuixqFQnSA4
  fdMcMSi02z1MYEn2JC-1EkVbWr4TqQgFP1EyymB6XjCWDiwTYd2xpK
  oUshu8WW601HLSgFIRUG3-cK_ZSdFaoWosIgAH5EQ2ayJkRB_7dXuo
  6_AYdIzMahvPz0n1yHHBlYBuYeR58V-x85ACeCGtzL2OptPa2TmWdA
  9Bi1MK6TYGZKezc6rpCK_VRSnLXhFwa1C3T0QBes",
  "tag": "doeAoagwJe9BwKayfcduiw"  
}]]></artwork></figure>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="jwm-attributes" title="JWM Attributes">
      <t>The JWM Attributes Set represents a JSON object whose members are the attributes conveyed by the JWM. The Attribute Names 
      within a JWM Attributes Set MUST be unique; JWM parsers MUST either reject JWMs with duplicate Attribute Names or use a JSON parser 
      that returns only the lexically last duplicate member name, as specified in Section 15.12 ("The JSON Object") of ECMAScript 5.1 <xref target="ECMAScript"/>.</t>

      <t>The set of attributes that a JWM must contain to be considered valid is context dependent and is outside the scope of this specification. 
      Specific applications of JWMs will require implementations to understand and process some attributes in particular ways.  However, in the absence 
      of such requirements, all attributes that are not understood by implementations MUST be ignored.</t>

      <t>There are three classes of JWM Attribute Names: Registered Attribute Names, Public Attribute Names and Private Attribute Names.</t>

      <section anchor="registered-attribute-names" title="Registered Attribute Names">
        <t>The following Attribute Names are registered in the IANA "JSON Web Message Attributes" registry established by <xref target="iana-considerations"/>.  None of the attributes
        defined below are intended to be mandatory to use or implement in all cases, but rather they provide a starting point for a set of useful, interoperable attributes. Applications 
        using JWMs should define which specific Attributes they use and when they are required or optional.</t>

        <section anchor="attributes-id" title="&quot;id&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "id" attribute is used to define a unique identifier for a JWM. The "id" attribute value MUST be assigned in a manner that ensures 
          that there is a negligible probability that the same value will be accidentally assigned to another JWM. The processing of this attribute 
          is generally application specific. The "id" attribute value is a case-sensitive string containing a StringOrURI value. Use of this attribute 
          is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-type" title="&quot;type&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "type" attribute is used to define the type of the message. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. The 
          "type" attribute value is a case-sensitive string containing a StringOrURI value. The "type" attribute value can be used by applications to 
          inform the structure and content of the "message body" and indicate the presence of other JWM attributes. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-body" title="&quot;body&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "body" attribute is used to define a location for application level message content. The "body" attribute value is a JSON object conforming
          to RFC 7159 <xref target="RFC7159"/>. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-to" title="&quot;to&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "to" attribute is used to define the intended recipients of the JWM. The "to" attribute value is an array of case-sensitive strings each 
          containing a StringOrURI value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-from" title="&quot;from&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "from" attribute is used to define the sender of the JWM. The "from" attribute value is a case-sensitive string containing a StringOrURI 
          value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-thread-id" title="&quot;thread_id&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "thread_id" attribute is used to associate the JWM to a group of related messages often referred to as a thread. The "thread_id" attribute value 
          is a case-sensitive string containing a StringOrURI value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute 
          is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-created-time" title="&quot;created_time&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "created_time" attribute is used to define the time in which the message was created. The "created_time" attributes value MUST be a number containing a 
          NumericDate value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-expires-time" title="&quot;expires_time&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "expires_time" attribute is used to define the lifespan or lifetime of the JWM. The "expires_time" attributes value MUST be a number containing a NumericDate 
          value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-reply-url" title="&quot;reply_url&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "reply_url" attribute is used to define a url to which a response to the message can be sent. The "reply_url" attribute value is a case-sensitive 
          string containing a StringOrURI value. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attributes-reply-to" title="&quot;reply_to&quot; Attribute">
          <t>The "reply_to" attribute is used to define who a response to the message should be sent to. The "reply_to" attribute value is a case-sensitive string 
          containing an array of case-sensitive strings containing StringOrURI values. The processing of this attribute is generally application specific. 
          Use of this attribute is OPTIONAL.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section anchor="public-attribute-names" title="Public Attribute Names">
        <t>Attribute Names can be defined at will by those using JWMs.  However, in order to prevent collisions, any new Attribute Name should either be 
        registered in the IANA "JSON Web Message Attributes" registry established by <xref target="iana-considerations"/> or be a Public Name: 
        a value that contains a Collision-Resistant Name. In each case, the definer of the name or value needs to take reasonable precautions to make sure they are in 
        control of the part of the namespace they use to define the Attribute Name.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="private-attribute-names" title="Private Attribute Names">
        <t>A producer and consumer of a JWM MAY agree to use Attribute Names that are Private Names: names that are not Registered Attribute Names <xref target="registered-attribute-names"/>
        or Public Attribute Names <xref target="public-attribute-names"/>.  Unlike Public Attribute Names, Private Attribute Names are subject to collision and should be used with caution.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="jose-header" title="JOSE Header">
      <t>For a JWM object, the members of the JSON object represented by the JOSE Header describe the cryptographic operations applied to the JWM
      and optionally, additional properties of the JWM. Depending upon whether the JWM is a JWS or JWE, the corresponding rules for the JOSE
      Header values apply.</t>

      <t>This specification further specifies the use of the following header parameters in both the cases where the JWM is a JWS and where 
      it is a JWE.</t>

      <section anchor="typ-type-header-parameter" title="&quot;typ&quot; (Type) Header Parameter">
        <t>The "typ" (type) Header Parameter defined by <xref target="RFC7515"/> and <xref target="RFC7516"/> is used by JWM applications 
        to declare the media type <xref target="IANA.MediaTypes"/> of this complete JWM.  This is intended for use by the JWM application
        when values that are not JWMs could also be present in an application data structure that can contain a JWM object; the application 
        can use this value to disambiguate among the different kinds of objects that might be present.  It will typically not be used by 
        applications when it is already known that the object is a JWM.  This parameter is ignored by JWM implementations; any processing of 
        this parameter is performed by the JWM application.  If present, it is RECOMMENDED that its value be "JWM" to indicate that this object 
        is a JWM.  While media type names are not case sensitive, it is RECOMMENDED that "JWM" always be spelled using uppercase characters for 
        compatibility with legacy implementations.  Use of this Header Parameter is OPTIONAL.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="cty-content-type-header-parameter" title="&quot;cty&quot; (Content Type) Header Parameter">
        <t>The "cty" (content type) Header Parameter defined by <xref target="RFC7515"/> and <xref target="RFC7516"/>
        is used by this specification to convey structural information about the JWM.</t>

        <t>In the normal case in which nested signing or encryption operations
        are not employed, the use of this Header Parameter is NOT
        RECOMMENDED.  In the case that nested signing or encryption is
        employed, this Header Parameter MUST be present; in this case, the
        value MUST be "JWM", to indicate that a Nested JWM is carried in this
        JWM.  While media type names are not case sensitive, it is
        RECOMMENDED that "JWM" always be spelled using uppercase characters
        for compatibility with legacy implementations.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="replicating-attributes-as-header-parameters" title="Replicating Attributes as Header Parameters">
        <t>In some applications using encrypted JWMs,
        it is useful to have an unencrypted representation of some attributes. 
        This might be used, for instance, in application processing rules to 
        determine whether and how to process the JWM before it is decrypted.</t>

        <t>This specification allows Attributes present in the JWM Attributes Set to be
        replicated as JOSE Header Parameters in a JWM that is a JWE, as needed by
        the application.  If such replicated attributes are present, the
        application receiving them SHOULD verify that their values are
        identical, unless the application defines other specific processing
        rules for these attributes.  It is the responsibility of the application
        to ensure that only attributes that are safe to be transmitted in an
        unencrypted manner are replicated as JOSE Header Parameter values in the
        JWM.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="creating-and-validating-jwms" title="Creating and Validating JWMs">
      <section anchor="creating-a-jwm" title="Creating a JWM">
        <t>To create a JWM, the following steps are performed. The order of the steps is not significant in cases where there 
        are no dependencies between the inputs and outputs of the steps.</t>

        <t><list style="numbers">
          <t>Create a JWM Attribute Set containing the desired attributes. Note that whitespace is explicitly allowed in the 
          representation and no canonicalization need be performed before encoding.</t>
          <t>Let the Message be the octets of the UTF-8 representation of the JWM Attributes Set.</t>
          <t>Create a JOSE Header containing the desired set of Header Parameters. The JWM MUST conform to either the JWS 
          <xref target="RFC7515"/> or JWE <xref target="RFC7516"/> specification. Note that whitespace is explicitly allowed 
          in the representation and no canonicalization need be performed before encoding.</t>
          <t>Depending upon whether the JWM is a JWS or JWE, there are two cases:</t>
        </list></t>

        <t><list style="symbols">
          <t>If the JWM is a JWS, create a JWS using the JWM Attribute Set as the JWS Payload; all steps specified in JWS <xref target="RFC7515"/> for creating a JWS MUST be followed. 
           If the resulting JWS features only a single signature, it can optionally be formated into JWS compact serialization format allowing the message to be URL safe. If however, 
           the resulting JWS features multiple signatures and URL safety for the message is still required, the entire JWS in JSON serialization format MUST be encoded to base64url format. Otherwise the output format 
           for the JWS MUST be JWS JSON serialization format.</t>
          <t>Else, if the JWM is a JWE, create a JWE using the JWM Attribute Set as the plaintext for the JWE; all steps specified in JWE <xref target="RFC7516"/> for creating a JWE MUST be followed. 
          If the resulting JWE features only a single recipient, it can optionally be formated into JWE compact serialization format allowing the message to be URL safe. If however, the 
          resulting JWE features multiple recipients and URL safety for the message is still required, the entire JWE in JSON serialization format MUST be encoded to base64url format. Otherwise the output format for 
          the JWE MUST be JWE JSON serialization format.</t>
        </list></t>

        <t><list style="numbers">
          <t>If a Nested JWM is desired, let the Message be the JWS or JWE, and return to Step 3, using a "cty" (content type) value of "JWM" in the new JOSE Header
          created in that step.</t>
          <t>Otherwise, let the resulting JWM be the JWS or JWE.</t>
        </list></t>
      </section>
      
      <section anchor="validating-a-jwm" title="Validating a JWM">
        <t>When validating a JWM, the following steps are performed. The order
        of the steps is not significant in cases where there are no
        dependencies between the inputs and outputs of the steps. If any of
        the listed steps fail, then the JWM MUST be rejected; that is,
        treated by the application as an invalid input.</t>
        <t><list style="numbers">
          <t>If the JWM is a valid base64url string containing at least one period ('.') character.
            <list style="numbers">
              <t>Let the Encoded JOSE Header be the portion of the JWM before the
              first period ('.') character.</t>
              <t>Base64url decode the Encoded JOSE Header following the
              restriction that no line breaks, whitespace, or other additional
              characters have been used.</t>
              <t>Verify that the resulting octet sequence is a UTF-8-encoded
              representation of a completely valid JSON object conforming to
              RFC 7159 <xref target="RFC7159"/>; let the JOSE Header be this JSON object.</t>
            </list>
          </t>
          <t>Else, if the JWM is a valid base64url string containing no period ('.') characters.
            <list style="numbers">
              <t>Let the Encoded JWS or JWE be the entire base64url string.</t>
              <t>Base64url decode the Encoded JWS or JWE following the
              restriction that no line breaks, whitespace, or other additional
              characters have been used.</t>
              <t>Verify that the resulting octet sequence is a UTF-8-encoded
              representation of a completely valid JSON object conforming to
              RFC 7159 <xref target="RFC7159"/>; let the JWS or JWE be this JSON object.</t>
            </list>
          </t>
          <t>Else, if the JWM is a UTF-8-encoded representation of a 
          completely valid JSON object conforming to RFC 7159 <xref target="RFC7159"/>; 
          let the JWS or JWE be this JSON object.</t>
          <t>Verify that the resulting JOSE Header includes only parameters
          and values whose syntax and semantics are both understood and
          supported or that are specified as being ignored when not
          understood.</t>
          <t>Determine whether the JWM is a JWS or a JWE using any of the
          methods described in Section 9 of <xref target="RFC7516"/>.</t>
          <t>Depending upon whether the JWM is a JWS or JWE, there are two
          cases:
            <list style="symbols">
            <t>If the JWM is a JWS, follow the steps specified in <xref target="RFC7515"/> for
            validating a JWS.  Let the Message be the result of base64url
            decoding the JWS Payload.</t>
            <t>Else, if the JWM is a JWE, follow the steps specified in
             <xref target="RFC7516"/> for validating a JWE.  Let the Message be the resulting
            plaintext.</t>
            </list>
          </t>
          <t>If the JOSE Header contains a "cty" (content type) value of
          "JWM", then the Message is a JWM that was the subject of nested
          signing or encryption operations.  In this case, return to Step
          1, using the Message as the JWM.</t>
          <t>Otherwise, base64url decode the Message following the
          restriction that no line breaks, whitespace, or other additional
          characters have been used.</t>
          <t>Verify that the resulting octet sequence is a UTF-8-encoded
          representation of a completely valid JSON object conforming to
          RFC 7159 <xref target="RFC7159"/>; let the JWM Attributes Set be this JSON object.</t>
        </list></t>

        <t>Finally, note that it is an application decision which algorithms may
        be used in a given context.  Even if a JWM can be successfully
        validated, unless the algorithms used in the JWM are acceptable to
        the application, it SHOULD reject the JWM.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="string-comparison-rules" title="String Comparison Rules">
        <t>These rules are identical to those applied to JWTs outlined in Section 7.3 of <xref target="RFC7519"/>.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="implementation-requirements" title="Implementation Requirements">
      <t>This section defines which algorithms and features of this
      specification are mandatory to implement.  Applications using this
      specification can impose additional requirements upon implementations
      that they use.</t>

      <t>Support for digitally signed JWMs using JWS is REQUIRED. Of the signature and 
      MAC algorithms specified in JSON Web Algorithms <xref target="RFC7518"/>, only 
      ECDSA using the P-256 curve and SHA-256 hash algorithm ("ES256") MUST be implemented 
      by conforming JWM implementations. It is RECOMMENDED that implementations also support
      ECDSA using the P-521 curve and the SHA-512 hash algorithm ("ES512") and EdDSA using the
      Ed25519 curve and SHA-512 hash algorithm. Support for other algorithms and key sizes is 
      OPTIONAL.</t>

      <t>Support for encrypted JWMs using JWE is also REQUIRED. Of the encryption algorithms
      specified in <xref target="RFC7518"/>, using Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral 
      Static (ECDH-ES) with the P-256 curve to agree upon a key and using 
      this key to to perform key wrapping of a Content Encryption Key ("ECDH-ES+A128KW" and 
      "ECDH-ES+A256KW") MUST be supported. With regards to content encryption, AES in 
      Galois/Counter Mode (GCM) with 128-bit and 256-bit keys ("A128GCM" and "A256GCM") 
      MUST also be supported. It is RECOMMENDED that implementations also support ECDH-ES and
      key wrapping variants using the X25519 curve also.</t>

      <t>Usage of the "none" algorithm identifier in a JWM as defined in the JOSE Web Algorithms section 3.6 
      <xref target="RFC7518"/> MUST be considered invalid.</t>

      <t>Support for Nested JWMs is also REQUIRED.</t>
    </section>
    
    <section anchor="iana-considerations" title="IANA Considerations">
      <section anchor="registration-template" title="Registration Template">
        <section anchor="attribute-name-registration-template" title="Attribute Name:">
          <t>The name requested (e.g., "type").  Because a core goal of this specification is for the resulting representations to be compact,
          it is RECOMMENDED that the name be short &#8211; that is, not to exceed 15 characters without a compelling reason to do so.  This name 
          is case sensitive.  Names may not match other registered names in a case-insensitive manner unless the Designated Experts state that 
          there is a compelling reason to allow an exception.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="attribute-description-registration-template" title="Attribute Description">
          <t>Brief description of the attribute (e.g., "Message Type").</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="change-controller-registration-template" title="Change Controller">
          <t>For Standards Track RFCs, list the "IESG".  For others, give the name of the responsible party.  Other details (e.g., postal address, 
          email address, home page URI) may also be included.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="specification-document-registration-template" title="Specification Document(s)">
          <t>Reference to the document or documents that specify the parameter, preferably including URIs that can be used to retrieve copies of 
          the documents.  An indication of the relevant sections may also be included but is not required.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="initial-registry-contents-registration-template" title="Initial Registry Contents">
          <t>o  Attribute Name: "id"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message ID<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "type"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Type<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "body"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Body<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "to"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Recipients<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "from"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message From<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "thread_id"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Thread ID<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "created_time"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Created Time<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "expires_time"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Expiry Time<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "reply_url"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Reply URL<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>

          <t>o  Attribute Name: "reply_to"<vspace/>
          o  Attribute Description: Message Reply To<vspace/>
          o  Change Controller:<vspace/>
          o  Specification Document(s):</t>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="media-type-registration" title="Media Type Registration">
       <section anchor="registry-contents" title="Registry Contents">
       </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="security-considerations" title="Security Considerations">
      <t>All of the security issues that are pertinent to any cryptographic
      application must be addressed by JWM/JWS/JWE/JWK agents.  Among these
      issues are protecting the user's asymmetric private and symmetric
      secret keys and employing countermeasures to various attacks.</t>

      <t>All the security considerations in the JWS specification also apply
      to JWM, as do the JWE security considerations when encryption is
      employed.  In particular, Sections 10.12 ("JSON Security
      Considerations") and 10.13 ("Unicode Comparison Security
      Considerations") of <xref target="RFC7515"/> apply equally to the JWM Attributes Set in the
      same manner that they do to the JOSE Header.</t>

      <section anchor="trust-decisions" title="Trust Decisions">
        <t>The contents of a JWM cannot be relied upon in a trust decision
        unless its contents have been cryptographically secured and bound to
        the context necessary for the trust decision.  In particular, the
        key(s) used to sign and/or encrypt the JWM will typically need to
        verifiably be under the control of the party identified by the associated
        cryptographic operation.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="signing-and-encryption-order" title="Signing and Encryption Order">
        <t>While syntactically the signing and encryption operations for Nested
        JWMs may be applied in any order, if both signing and encryption are
        necessary, normally producers should sign the message and then
        encrypt the result (thus encrypting the signature).  This prevents
        attacks in which the signature is stripped, leaving just an encrypted
        message, as well as providing privacy for the signer.  Furthermore,
        signatures over encrypted text are not considered valid in many
        jurisdictions.</t>

        <t>Note that potential concerns about security issues related to the
        order of signing and encryption operations are already addressed by
        the underlying JWS and JWE specifications; in particular, because JWE
        only supports the use of authenticated encryption algorithms,
        cryptographic concerns about the potential need to sign after
        encryption that apply in many contexts do not apply to this
        specification.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="privacy-considerations" title="Privacy Considerations">
      <t>A JWM may contain privacy-sensitive information.  When this is the
      case, measures MUST be taken to prevent disclosure of this
      information to unintended parties.  One way to achieve this is to use
      an encrypted JWM and authenticate the recipient.  Another way is to
      ensure that JWMs containing unencrypted privacy-sensitive information
      are only transmitted using protocols utilizing encryption that
      support endpoint authentication, such as Transport Layer Security
      (TLS).  Omitting privacy-sensitive information from a JWM is the
      simplest way of minimizing privacy issues.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">
    <t>The authors of this draft would like to acknowledge the 
    following individuals for the significant contribution of ideas and 
    time spent reviewing this document:<vspace/>
    Kyle Den Hartog<vspace/>
    Daniel Hardman<vspace/>
    Troy Ronda<vspace/>
    Troy Ronda<vspace/></t>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title='Normative References'>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.2119.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7519.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7515.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7516.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7518.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7159.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8174.xml'?>
      <reference anchor="IANA.MediaTypes" target="http://www.iana.org/assignments/media-types">
        <front>
          <title>Media Types</title>
          <author>
            <organization>IANA</organization>
          </author>
          <date/>
        </front>
      </reference>
      <reference anchor="ECMAScript" target="http://www.ecma-international.org/ecma-262/5.1/ECMA-262.pdf">
        <front>
          <title>ECMAScript Language Specification, 5.1 Edition</title>
          <author>
            <organization>Ecma International</organization>
          </author>
          <date month="June" year="2011"/>
        </front>
	      <seriesInfo name="ECMA Standard" value="262"/>
      </reference>
    </references>
  </back>
</rfc>

